本视频由Dashlane赞助
This video is supported by Dashlane.
今年5月 Atlas V火箭将一搜机密的航天飞机发射入轨
Back in May of this year, the Atlas V rocket lifted off the pad, carrying a secret space plane into orbit.
由美国空军负责的X37飞行器在过去10年中有8年是在太空度过的
Operated by the US Space Force, the X37 has spent 8 of the last 10 years in space.
而它现在正要打破之前的记录 并测试一项新的技术
Now it is looking to beat it's previous record and test out a new form of technology
该技术可能对地球上的生活产生巨大影响
which could have a massive impact here on Earth.
X37会进行将会进行首次太空太阳能发电厂测试
The X37 will perform the first ever test of a solar power farm in space.
该想法认为太空中的大型太阳能阵列可以收集大量的能量
The idea is that a large solar array in space could gather an enormous amount of energy from the sun
并无线传输给地球任意一个角落
and wirelessly transmit power to anywhere on Earth.
这个想法的出现已经有一阵子了
This idea has been around for a while -
但目前为止发射并在太空测试这么大的物件成本实在太高
but the cost of actually launching and testing something this large has always been too high - until now.
由于猎鹰九号火箭将发射成本极大降低
Due to the incredibly low cost of the Falcon 9,
太空叉正在开始用他们规模庞大的互联网卫星星座来彻底改变宽带行业
SpaceX are starting to revolutionize the broadband industry
with their gigantic constellation of internet satellites.
随着进入太空越来越方便
With space becoming more and more accessible,
能源公司也将可以把他们的业务搬到太空
it could allow energy companies to move their business into space.
在晴朗的日子里
On a perfectly sunny day,
地球上一米见方的面积能接受250W左右的太阳能
a one by one meter of land on Earth would typically receive around 250 Watts of power from the sun.
即使最高效的太阳能板也只能将其中的20%转化为电能
Even the most efficient solar panels can only turn about 20% of that energy into electricity.
而在太空中的太阳能板则能接收超过两倍于地面的太阳能功率
A solar panel in space would receive more than double the amount of power from the sun
因为太空不会受到大气层的遮挡
since it isn't being blocked by our atmosphere.
当太阳的能量照射到太阳能板上时 它会被转化为电能
As the Sun's energy hits the solar panel it gets converted into electricity.
这些电能可以被转化为微波信号 并以无线方式传送到地球上
That electricity could then be converted into a microwave signal and beamed wirelessly down to Earth.
这些微波信号可以以特定的频率进行传输
These microwaves could be transmitted at a specific frequency,
使它们能够穿过云层且不会对地球上的生命造成伤害
allowing them to pass through the clouds without causing harm to life on Earth.
为了接收这些能量 地面上需要建造一个大型的天线阵列
In order to receive this power, a large farm of rectennas would be built on the ground
将接收到的微波转换成电能
to convert the incoming microwaves into electricity.
微波传到地球上后会扩散很远
As the microwaves travel down to Earth, they spread out over a large distance.
所以天线阵列可能要几公里宽才能利用所有的能量
This means the farm would need to be several kilometers wide in order to harness all of the power.
但如果不把这些能量传送到地面 而是传送给飞机呢？
But instead of transmitting this power to the ground, what if we used it to power airplanes?
虽然许多行业已经开始推广新能源了
Although many industries have moved over to more renewable energy sources,
但航空工业仍然面临着能量密度的巨大挑战
the airline industry still faces a massive challenge in the form of energy density.
飞机存储能量靠的是燃油 而电动飞机靠的是电池
An airplane stores its energy in the form of fuel while an electric plane stores its energy in batteries.
为了存储同样多的能量
In order to store the same amount of energy,
电动飞机需要大量的电池 导致最终比普通飞机重40倍
an electric airplane ends up almost 40 times heavier due to the amount of batteries it needs.
对于飞机来说 这些额外的重量大大降低了它的航程与运力
For an airplane, this extra weight drastically reduces how far it can fly and how many passengers it can hold.
最近 一架塞斯纳电动飞机在华盛顿上空进行了首次试飞
Recently, an electric Cessna airplane took to the skies over Washington to perform its first ever test flight.
这已经是世界上最大的电动载客飞机了
This is the world's largest electric passenger plane,
但它只能载9名乘客飞行160公里
but it can only carry 9 passengers a distance of 160km.
但如果我们能移除电动飞机上的绝大多数电池
But what if we could remove most of the batteries from an electric plane
并在飞行中给它持续不断提供能量呢？
and provide a constant source of power throughout the flight?
太空中的发电厂可以将能量传送给地球
While a solar farm in space could beam power down to Earth,
理论上也可以将能量传送给移动中的目标 比如飞机轮船 甚至其他在轨卫星
it could theoretically beam the power to moving targets like planes, ships and even other satellites in orbit.
为了最大限度地将电力输送到飞机上
In order to maximize the amount of power being sent to an aircraft,
可以先把能量转换成激光束 而不是微波
the power could be converted into laser light instead of microwaves
然后直接发射到飞机的太阳能电池阵列上
and beamed directly onto the plane's solar array.
这就可以用更窄的光束传输更多的能量
This would allow more power to be transferred in a much narrower beam.
飞机飞行高度也在地球最厚的那部分大气层的上空
Since planes fly well above the thickest parts of our atmosphere,
云和雾之类并不会挡住能量束
things like clouds and fog wouldn't get in the way of the power beam.
可以让飞机可以有比地面更小的接收装置
This would allow the plane to have much smaller receivers than those used on the ground.
放置在地球静止轨道上的太阳能发电站星座
A constellation of solar farms placed in a geostationary orbit
甚至可以为夜晚飞行的飞机提供持续的电力
could provide constant power even to an aircraft flying through the night.
虽然到那时电动飞机仍然需要电池进行起飞和降落
Although an electric plane would still need a battery pack for takeoff and landing,
但大部分电池可以减掉 换来更多的客舱空间 从而提升运力
the majority of batteries could be stripped out and replaced with cabin space for passengers and cargo.
当飞机穿出云层 太空发电厂就会锁定飞行中的飞机
Once the plane is above the clouds, the solar farm would lock onto the moving aircraft
并对飞机的太阳能板持续供能
and start beaming power continuously to the plane's solar arrays.
这听起来可能是对未来的不靠谱的设想
This may seem like a crazy idea from the future,
但其中多数技术已经经过了测试
but most of the technologies involved have already been tried and tested.
早在2003年 NASA工程师就曾用10千瓦的激光来为一架模型飞机太阳能板供能
Back in 2003, NASA engineers flew a model airplane by beaming a 10kW laser at its solar array.
2008年 工程师们从毛伊岛的一座山顶上将20瓦的功率
In 2008, engineers beamed 20 watts of power from a mountain top in Maui
发射向了150公里外夏威夷岛的接收器
down to a receiver 150km away on the island of Hawaii.
X37上的实验将是有史以来第一次在太空中对太阳能发电厂的测试
The experiment onboard the X37 will be the first ever real life test of a solar power farm in space.
尽管太空中的太阳能发电厂会带来极大的好处
Despite the amazing benefits a solar farm in space would offer,
但开发这些技术的成本仍然很高
the cost to develop all of these different technologies is still too high.
而如今 随着太空已俨然成为私人公司的游乐场
But with space now becoming a playground for private companies,
我们利用大气层外的能量这件事可能并不遥远
it seems almost inevitable
that one day we'll be harnessing the enormous amounts of energy just outside our atmosphere.
随着太空叉逐渐部署他们的Starlink星座
As SpaceX starts to roll out their Starlink constellation,
它将在未来为数百万目前无法访问的人提供互联网服务
it will provide internet to millions of people that currently don't have access.
Although the majority of the world is well accustomed to the internet by now,
most of us still have a hard time remembering all of our passwords.
Dashlane is the best way to manage and remember all of your passwords, personal data and payment information so you don't have to.
When you sign up to Dashlane you choose a master password which will never leave your device.
Every time you sign up to a website, Dashlane generates a long and complicated password which is encrypted using your master password.
This keeps all of your passwords secure and means you only ever need to remember one password.
It's incredibly simple and works across everything.
They also have a VPN which protects all of your private data.
To save yourself the hassle of filling out forms and resetting passwords, try Dashlane for free on your first device by visiting dashlane.com/primalspace.
Then, when you want to upgrade to premium use the code primalspace.
This is not only a great way to try out a free product but a great way to support the channel.
Thank you very much for watching and I'll see you in the next video.